(
"ai_sub_version": "1.10.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
告知あり♡
Announcements included ♡
ゲストあり♡
Guests included ♡
猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026
うぇあどくっきー WeirdCookies
Okayu Nekomata Birthday Festival 2026
WeirdCookies
2/22
BIRTHDAY LIVE
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always cause so much trouble,
いつもさんざん困らせちゃうけど
and I'm always making things difficult,
それでも隣にいてくれる
but even so, you stay by my side.
君のそばにずっと
I'll be beside you forever.
Watch me!
曖昧な言葉じゃ
With vague words,
真面目な君には伝わらない
I can't reach a serious person like you.
頑丈なそのハートを
That sturdy heart of yours,
覗いてみたい
I want to peek inside.
溶かしてみたい
I want to melt it.
そんな時 こんな魔法はどうかな
At times like that, how about a spell like this?
何が出るかな
I wonder what will come out?
やっちゃえ せーの
Let's do it! Ready, go!
ふわふわだっていいの
It's okay to be light and fluffy.
Which one to be magic?
Watch me the magic
あらら想像以上の展開
Oh my, things are unfolding beyond my imagination.
もう止められないのよ
I can't stop it anymore.
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
溢れる思いで空回り
Spinning my wheels with overflowing feelings.
振りかけるハッピーなイメージ
Sprinkling a happy image,
手振り回すファンシーなマジック
waving my hands in fancy magic.
また君にくどくど言われちゃうけど
You'll probably nag me again,
ほらこんな Day by day
but look, day by day like this,
あの日から Fall in love with you
since that day, I've fallen in love with you.
変わらないから ずっと Only you
Because it won't change, it'll always be only you.
だからほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, there's no time to be idle.
掴め ハッピーエンディング
Seize that happy ending.
いつまでも隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to be laughing by your side forever.
いつも仲間外れで
Always being an outcast,
ひとりぼっちの毎日
every day spent all alone.
そんな私の前に現れた君は
When you appeared before a person like me,
同じ寂しさを抱えている
you were carrying the same loneliness.
とてもとても優しい人
A very, very kind person.
今も心配事は多いけど
There are still many things to worry about,
もう私も君もひとりじゃないさ
but now, neither I nor you are alone.
眩しくて愛おしいこの日々が
These dazzling, precious days...
ずっと続きますように
I hope they continue forever.
1 2
飛ばせハッピーなイメージ
Let those happy images fly!
とびきりのファンシーなマジック
With the ultimate fancy magic.
また君にクドクド言われそうだけれど
I'll probably get nagged by you again,
そんな目一杯Take it
But I'll give it my all—take it!
あの日からFalling love with you
Ever since that day, I'm falling in love with you.
気づいてほしいのLove with you
I want you to notice, I'm in love with you.
だからこそウダウダしてる場合じゃないの
That's why there's no time to be indecisive.
次はどんなプランニング
What kind of planning is next?
そしてまた今日もハプニング
And another happening again today.
明日はどんなおかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what strange things will happen tomorrow.
ずっと隣で見ててね
Watch me from right by my side forever.
ハッピーなイメージ
A happy image!
ファンシーなマジック
Fancy magic!
ハッピーなイメージ
A happy image!
ファンシーなマジック
Fancy magic!
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに
Thank you so much for coming
来てくれてありがとー！
to my birthday live today!
改めまして、もぐもぐー？
Once again—Mogu Mogu?
おかゆー！
Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
本日はこちら
Please tweet a lot today
ハッシュタグ猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026で
using the hashtag
いっぱい呟いてください！
#猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026!
ライブ終わった後すぐ見に行っちゃうんだからね
I'm going to check them out right after the live.
そして、みんな見て？
And everyone, look at this.
今回のライブは「ウィアードクッキー」という
I've titled this live
タイトルを付けました
'Weird Cookie.'
「ウィアード」っていうのは
The word 'Weird'
「奇妙」っていう意味があるんだけど
can mean 'strange' or 'peculiar,'
なんでウィアードって付けたのかなーとか
but I'd be happy if you watched while wondering
考えながらライブを見てくれると
why I chose that specific name.
嬉しいなって思っているよ
そして見て！ このステージ！
And look! Look at this stage!
とっても可愛いでしょ？
It's super cute, isn't it?
でも、可愛いだけじゃないんだよ
But it's not just cute.
凄いね、曲によってガラッと雰囲気
It's amazing! They made it so that the atmosphere
変わるように作っていただいたので
changes completely depending on the song.
そこもね、注目してみてください
So please, keep an eye out for that.
「へー」ってなるかもしれないね
You might go 'Huh!' at some points.
そしてゲストも今回盛りだくさんでございます！
And we have a ton of guests this time too!
ワクワクドキドキ、あ、僕も今から
I'm so excited—Wait, I'm already worrying
ちゃんと振り付けとか歌とかいけるのかなーと
if I can handle the choreography and singing.
思いつつも...
ではね、みんなと楽しく自分の誕生日を
Anyway, I hope we can all have fun together
お祝いできたらなと思っております
celebrating my birthday.
そして最後に、最後に！
And finally—finally!
みんなに喜んでもらえるような告知
I have an announcement ready
用意してあるので
that I think you'll all enjoy.
ぜひ最後まで楽しんでもらえればなと
So please, stick around and enjoy until the very end.
思っております
ふふっ、次の曲いってみよっか
Hehe. Let's head into the next song.
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君が独り
Hey, I already know. You're all alone.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
ビクンビクン震えてさ
You're twitching and trembling,
声もダダ漏れなんだわ
and your voice is leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ
Just be honest. It's obvious, so just say it.
聞いてんの？ フツフツ恥ずかしい
Are you listening? It's bubbling with embarrassment.
みんな隠しているだけ
Everyone's just hiding it.
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君が独り
Hey, I already know. That you're alone
涙してるの 知ってるよ
and crying. I know.
グスングスンへこんでさ
Sniffling and feeling down.
弱音吐いたらいいんだよ
It's okay to show some weakness.
朝が来るまで一緒拘束
I'll keep you tied up until morning.
もっと泣いたって何度だって
Cry more, as many times as you want,
受け止めてあげる
I'll accept it all.
もう我慢しないでいっぱだしてね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
ワァ！ お願い君が欲しいの
Wah! Please, I want you.
慰めさせてシェイクシェイク
Let me comfort you, shake shake.
愛の才能で泣いてくれなきゃ枯れてしまう
If you don't cry for my love talent, I'll wither away.
濡れていたい 泣いていたいでしょう？
You want to be wet, you want to be crying, right?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
I want to lick it up and drink it all down.
ワァ！ お願い君が欲しいの
Wah! Please, I want you.
頼り散らしてシェイクなんて最高ね
Leaning on me and shaking is just the best.
わけてくれなきゃ君の痛い
Unless you share it, I want to feel
感じてたい 泣いていたいでしょう？
your pain. You want to be crying, right?
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I want to suck it out and save you.
見たい見たい見たい見たい...
I want to see, I want to see, I want to see...
ねえ あたし知ってるよ
君がひとり悔しがってんの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
I know you're regretting it all alone.
ズキュン ズキュン 高まるじゃん
君を推すことをやめない
My heart's pounding.
I won't stop supporting you.
ねえ あたしも知ってるよ
君はできる子 知ってるよ
Hey, I know too.
I know you can do it.
辛い時は 弱いくらいでちょうどいい
あたしそれですらも好きだよ
When times are tough, being weak is just fine.
I love even that part of you.
MWAH!! お願い 君が欲しいの
名前を呼んでよ
MWAH!! Please, I want you.
Call my name.
いつだって 会いに参上
君はひとりだ
I'll come see you anytime.
You're alone.
だから歌う ひとりじゃない
もういいでしょ
So I'll sing. You're not alone.
Isn't that enough?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば
I'm telling you, solo play is over.
君が病めるときも
Even when you're sick,
あたしそばにいるわ
I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'll always be watching over you.
そうよ怖くないのよ
Yes, don't be afraid.
MWAH!! お願い 君が欲しいの
慰めさせて
MWAH!! Please, I want you.
Let me comfort you.
SHAKE SHAKE 愛の才能で
泣いてくれなきゃ
SHAKE SHAKE With the talent of love,
if you don't cry...
困ってしまう 濡れていたい
ねぇいいでしょ
I'll be in trouble. I want to be wet,
isn't that okay?
舐めとって飲み干したいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to lick it all up
and drink it down.
MWAH!! お願い 君が欲しいの
頼り散らして
MWAH!! Please, I want you.
Lean on me.
SHAKE UP! なんて最高ね
分けてくれなきゃ
SHAKE UP! It's the best, isn't it?
If you don't share it with me...
君の痛い 感じてたい
慰めてたい
I want to feel your pain.
I want to comfort you.
吸いとって救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to suck it all out
and save you.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ
君がひとり涙してんの
Hey, I know.
I know you're crying all alone.
知ってるよ ぐすぐすエコーを聴かせて
弱い子からいいんじゃない
I know. Let me hear your sniffling echoes.
Isn't it fine for a weak kid?
朝が来るまでイチャコら
もっと泣いたって
Flirting until morning comes.
Even if you cry more...
何度だって受け止めてあげる
もう我慢しないで出していこ
I'll accept you any number of times.
Don't hold back anymore, let it out.
ってば そう
I'm telling you, so...
自堕落の優等生
今宵も自分と密会で
Self-deprecating honor student.
Having a secret meeting with myself tonight too.
しんどいわ しんどいわ
ぱつらつらご唱和
It's tough, it's tough.
Join me in the chant.
本当は劣等生
あたしはあたしに不詳です
Actually a failure.
I'm unknown even to myself.
しんどいわ しんどいわ
もういやいや絶交
It's tough, it's tough.
No more, no more, breaking off ties.
シンバイミョウ シンバイミョウ
これは笑えるジョークさ
Deep mystery, deep mystery.
This is a funny joke.
シンマイドウ シンマイドウ
みんなおいでよポップさ
Deep truth, deep truth.
Everyone, come join the pop.
まあまあ それをお刺すよ
ただの噛み切りですよ
Well, well, I'll pierce that.
It's just a paper cut.
いいから 早く箱 押せや
Whatever, just press the box already.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
あくまほどっさようなら
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
Goodbye to the demons.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
愛してほしいじゃん
I've died, I've died.
I want you to love me.
それでもハマっちゃうなら
それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even if you get hooked on it,
even if you fall in love...
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
エンジェル エンジェル
I've died, I've died.
Angel, angel.
わあ! 悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Whoa! Bad news, bad news...
汚いね
It's dirty, isn't it?
飛べないね
Can't fly, can't fly.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
I've died, I've died.
本当の天使 スルーしてご臨終
Ignoring the real angel, it's the end.
あくまで天使じゃん 最強じゃん
I'm just an angel, after all.
I'm the strongest, right?
君がためって名言の悪意 悪意
The malice in the saying 'for your sake'...
夢が叶うって奪ったさらり さらり
Quietly stolen away the 'dreams come true'...
高中毒性の高いものにゃ
贖うんだな
If it's highly addictive,
you've gotta pay the price.
魂抜かれちゃって やーねやーね
Soul's been snatched away.
How awful, how awful.
光り輝く若辺 この首が締まってく
A shining youth, this neck is being tightened.
嘘をつけば緩んでく 言えないSOS
If I tell a lie, it loosens.
An unspoken SOS.
白いペンキ被りましょう
成り切ってしまいましょう
Let's cover ourselves in white paint.
Let's act the part completely.
嘘をつけば楽になる ほらやっちゃって
If you tell a lie, it gets easier.
Go on, just do it.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
死んじゃった 死んじゃった ああ
I've died, I've died. Ahh.
それでも穿っちゃうけど
それでも嫌っちゃうけど
Even if I doubt it,
even if I hate it...
成り切って笑顔で エンジェル エンジェル
Acting with a smile,
Angel, Angel.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
あくまほどっさようなら
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
Goodbye to the demons.
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
愛してほしいじゃん
I've died, I've died.
I want you to love me.
それでもハマっちゃうなら
それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even if you get hooked on it,
even if you fall in love...
死んじゃった 死んじゃった (HEY!!)
I've died, I've died. (HEY!!)
わあ! 悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Whoa! Bad news, bad news...
汚いね
It's dirty, isn't it?
飛べないね
Can't fly, can't fly.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I've died, I've died.
本当の天使 スルーしてご臨終
Ignoring the real angel, it's the end.
悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Bad news, bad news...
醜いね
It's ugly, isn't it?
映えないね
Doesn't look good, does it?
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil!
死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I've died, I've died.
本当の悪魔になっても プレイヤ
Even if I become a real demon, Player.
あくまで天使じゃん 最強じゃん
I'm just an angel, after all.
I'm the strongest, right?
充電器を貸して!
Lend me your charger!
またあなたのせいで あたし擦り減った
Because of you again, I'm worn down.
終電見逃して!
Miss the last train!
またあたしのせいで 帰れなくなった
Because of me again, we can't go home.
鮮やかに落ち込んで
Vividly depressed
お互いに足を引っ張った
We dragged each other down
晴れ沈殿した思い出と
With the memories that precipitated clearly
ずっというっしょ
Together forever
参観日にだって
Even on parent-teacher conference days
誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
I felt like no one was looking at me
散々しに勝って
Winning over the messiness
君の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
I tried not to expect anything from your town
そうやって守った孤独さえ
Even the loneliness I protected like that
めちゃくちゃになった
Has been completely messed up
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I'm always wanting to die, I can't help it
こんな顔大事にしたいと思えないもん
I don't feel like I want to treasure a face like this
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together
ささやかな幸せが
The modest happiness
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope it becomes an irreplaceable trauma
離ればなれなんて
Being separated or something
誰かが吐かせたバグだよね
Is a bug that someone made up, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll live with you as your lifelong regret
大切なものって何？
What's the most important thing?
今失くしたそれ
The thing you just lost
あたしと間違い犯しちゃったんだ
You've made a mistake with me
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health
グロい履歴の中で
In our grotesque history
ずっというっしょ
Together forever
もうちょっと普通に
A little more normally
悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to think sad things are sad
長調のチューンに
To a major-key tune
感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to entrust my feelings and be at ease
せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね
Please live as hard as you can
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I'm always wanting to die, I can't help it
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the mercy of a song like that
あなただけ一人で
You, all by yourself
あたしの目を盗んで
Stealing my gaze
幸せになろうなんて思わないで
Don't you dare think of becoming happy
髪を乾かしてくれた night から
From the night you dried my hair
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I've been broken, you know
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll live with you as your lifelong regret
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that won't come off
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている
It keeps flashing back over and over
最低だよ
You're the worst
一緒に居た時の方が
The time when we were together
あたし可愛かったなあ
I was cuter back then
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll live with you as your lifelong regret
大切なものって何？
What's the most important thing?
今失くしたそれ
The thing you just lost
あたしと間違い犯しちゃったんだ
You've made a mistake with me
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health
他の誰かと眠っていても
Even if you're sleeping with someone else
お揃いの悪夢でずっというっしょ
Together forever in matching nightmares
愛スクリーム！
Ice Cream!
教えて！ もっとあなたのこと
Tell me! More about you
Tell me m-m-m-m, tell me m-m-m-m
聞かせて！ もっとあなたの声
Let me hear! More of your voice
Let me h-m-m-m-m, let me h-m-m-m-m
こんなドキドキもう抑えきれない
I can't suppress this heart-pounding anymore
Oh, I need you. All I need is you.
友達は卒業 運命の私
Graduating from friends, fated me
見つけてほしいの
I want you to find me
勇気を出して
Pluck up your courage
見つめる作戦
Staring strategy
目が合えば
If our eyes meet
止められない Yeah yeah yeah
Can't stop, yeah yeah yeah
この恋この愛で
With this love, this affection
メルメル溶けちゃうよ
It'll melt away
ねえねえねえ
Hey hey hey
気づいてマイダーリン
Notice me my darling
届け大好き
Reach you, I love you
スクリーム！ スクリーム！
Scream! Scream!
叫びましょう
Let's shout
スクリーム！
Scream!
アイスクリーム！
Ice Cream!
スクリーム！ スクリーム！
Scream! Scream!
叫びましょう
Let's shout
スクリーム！
Scream!
アイスクリーム！
Ice Cream!
ルーナちゃん！
Luna-chan!
はーい！ 何が好き？
Yes! What do you like?
チョコミントよりもあなた！
More than chocolate mint, I like you!
わためちゃん！
Watame-chan!
はーい！ 何が好き？
Yes! What do you like?
ストロベリーフレイバーよりもあなた！
More than strawberry flavor, I like you!
おかゆちゃん！
Okayu-chan!
はーい！ 何が好き？
Yes! What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりもあなた！
More than cookies & cream, I like you!
みんなー！
Everyone!
はーい！ 何が好き？
Yes! What do you like?
もちろん大好き アイスクリーム！
Of course, I love ice cream!
止められない Yeah yeah yeah
Can't stop, yeah yeah yeah
この恋この愛で
With this love, this affection
メルメル溶けちゃうよ
It'll melt away
ねえねえねえ
Hey hey hey
気づいてマイダーリン
Notice me my darling
届け大好き
Reach you, I love you
スクリーム！ スクリーム！
Scream! Scream!
叫びましょう
Let's shout
スクリーム！
Scream!
アイスクリーム！
Ice Cream!
叫びましょう
Let's shout it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream! Ice cream!
お願い見つけて マイダーリン
Please find me, my darling
お願い気付いて マイダーリン
Please notice me, my darling
勇気を出して
Gather your courage
近づく作戦
The strategy to get closer
手と手が触れて
Our hands touch
止められない
I can't stop it
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で メルメル溶けちゃうよ
Yeah yeah yeah, with this love and affection, I'm melting away
ねえねえねえ 気付いてマイダーリン それはあなた
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling—that person is you
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's shout it out
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream
La la la...
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな ファンタジックな物語が
Like magic, like a dream, a fantastic story
世界に感染 愉快に蔓延 待ってそんなの聞いてないってば
Infecting the world, spreading joyfully—wait, I didn't hear about this!
根本的に痛い
Fundamentally painful
異常鼓動支えてイカレた妄想量
Supporting an abnormal pulse, a crazy amount of delusion
本能的に深い
Instinctively deep
破壊衝動照らす確かな解像度
The certain resolution illuminating the destructive impulse
恋の導火線 いざ火を灯し
The fuse of love, lighting it now
ひとつここらで本調子
Getting into full swing right about here
脳細胞に今 叩き込め
Now, hammer it into my brain cells
分からないことだらけを
Full of things I don't understand
あざとい際どい笑わないで
Calculating and risky, please don't laugh
いつもいつも誤魔化しては
Always, always deceiving yourself
借りね いらない 知らない おだてないで
A debt, I don't need it, I don't know it, don't flatter me
言えない消えない思い込め
With feelings that can't be said or erased
愛の強制ミューティレーション
Love's forced mutilation
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな ファンタジックな物語が
Like magic, like a dream, a fantastic story
世界に感染 愉快に蔓延 待ってそんなの聞いてないダーリン
Infecting the world, spreading joyfully—wait, I didn't hear about this, darling
ベタな恋愛 エラな展開 だってそれじゃつまらないでしょ
A cliché romance, a bizarre turn of events—because that would be boring, wouldn't it?
切り抜けて 引き付けて 愛の画面ストレート
Cutting through, drawing them in, love's screen straight
根本的にまずい 異常鼓動支えてイカレた情報量
Fundamentally bad—supporting an abnormal pulse, a crazy amount of information
圧倒的に淡い 母性本能暴く飢えた奴隷根性
Overwhelmingly faint—exposing maternal instinct, a starving slave mentality
恋の導火線 いざ火を付けて 頭の中はアルデンテ
The fuse of love, lighting it now—my head is al dente
生細胞に今 流し込め 抗いがたいことだらけを
Now, pour it into the living cells—all the things that are hard to resist
冷たい触れ合い遊ばないで
A cold interaction, don't play around
いつもいつも当てつけては
Always, always being spiteful
借りね 拙い 伺い ふざけないで
A debt, clumsy, an inquiry—don't mess with me
言えない消えない思い込め 愛の完結アイスピック
With feelings that can't be said or erased, love's conclusion: an ice pick
好きな人の好きな人ってだけで嫌い
I hate you just because you're the person my crush likes
都合の良い子 エディテイション 終わりたくないんだよ
A convenient girl, 'Edit-ation'—I don't want it to end
狂った未来に迎合 終わった抵抗 いっそこのまま目塞いで
Catering to a crazy future, resistance is over—might as well keep my eyes closed
切って爽快 喰らって崩壊 知って後快 望んだ将来
Cutting is refreshing, eating is collapsing, knowing is regret—the future I wanted
手を繋いで 場を繋いで ファンタジックなすったもんだが
Holding hands, keeping the flow, a fantastic fuss...
脳に感染 危険に発展 待ってこんな...
Infecting the brain, developing into danger—wait, this kind of...
…も聞いてないってダーリン
...not listening to a word, Darling.
ベタな恋愛　エラな展開
A cliché romance, a flawed development.
だってそれじゃつまらないでしょ
Because that would be boring, wouldn't it?
踏みつけて　焼き付けて
Trample it down, sear it in.
とろけそうな　三叉神経
A trigeminal nerve about to melt.
壊れそうな　群居本能
A gregarious instinct about to break.
崩れそうな　楔を前に
Before a wedge about to crumble.
愛の呪い　レボリューション
The curse of love, a revolution.
ドキメキ　メキキリュウに
On the thumping current...
私は乗っている　きっとね
...I am riding, I'm sure.
ドキメキダイアリー
作詞・作曲：Chinozo
Dokimeki Diary
Lyrics/Music: Chinozo
なんか言葉にできないこと
Things I can't quite put into words.
ちょっと心臓さわぐこと
Things that make my heart flutter a bit.
なんとなく今日照らすこと
Things that somehow brighten the day.
ちょっと好みの花見つけた
I found a flower I like a little.
広いけれど　かりそめだってさ
It's vast, but they say it's ephemeral.
欲しいものさえ探せないよ
I can't even find the things I want.
ワクワクしたそのダイアリー
That diary I was so excited about...
セラムンぷりして放り出すなんて
...acting all cool and throwing it away.
イヤイヤイヤイヤ
No, no, no, no...
やるせなくなっちゃうわ
woh-oh woh-oh-oh
...it just makes me feel helpless.
でもだけどきっと可能性あり
But still, there's surely a possibility.
気持ちいい風に浮遊して
Floating on a pleasant breeze.
ずっとずっとちょっともっといつかは飛べたらいいな
I wish I could fly away someday, further and further.
ドキメキ　メキキリュウに
On the thumping current...
私は乗っている　きっとね
...I am riding, I'm sure.
わからない物語にビビらないで
Don't be afraid of the unknown story.
キラキラ空想に
In a sparkling fantasy...
世界が踊る　笑って
...the world dances. Smile!
縮こまってる時間はないな
There's no time to be shrinking back.
私を知りたい
I want to know myself.
何もかもがまだわからないないない
I don't know anything at all yet.
私は見つけたい
I want to find it.
「行ってきます」を声にできたなら
If only I could say, "I'm heading out."
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
Maybe I've become a little bit of an adult.
ちゃっちゃかちゃ深呼吸
Taking deep breaths, one by one.
優しく歩くたび失速
Slowing down every time I walk gently.
つまんない筆跡は夢がない
Boring handwriting lacks dreams.
ちょっとキライな自分見つけた
I found a part of myself I dislike a bit.
黒い霧を追って雨に打たれて
Chasing the black mist, caught in the rain...
帰りたくなるの
...I just want to go home.
ワクワクしたそのダイアリー
That diary I was so excited about...
少し浮かされて走り出すなんて
...starting to run, feeling a bit uplifted.
マイアイアイアイアイ
My, ay-ay-ay-ay...
遮二無二で行こうわ
woh-oh woh-oh-oh
...let's go forward recklessly!
お気にのアクセはなくしたくないの
I don't want to lose my favorite accessory.
woh-oh woh-oh-oh
まだ何も分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand anything yet.
woh-oh woh-oh-oh
好きって気持ちに向かいたい
I want to head towards that feeling of love.
あの星のように輝きたい　oh
I want to shine like that star, oh.
ドキメキ　メキキリュウに
On the thumping current...
私は乗っている　きっとね
...I am riding, I'm sure.
やっぱりイヤイヤイヤイヤ
答えのない世界で生きてるせいです
After all, it's no, no, no, no...
all because we live in a world with no answers.
未来は優秀に
The future is excellent...
待っても変わらないし　叫んで
...but it won't change if you just wait. Shout out!
私らしくありたい
I want to be myself.
ドキメキ　メキキリュウを
Beyond the thumping current...
乗り越えた先には
...that I've overcome...
イヤイヤイヤイヤ
わからない物語が待っている
...no, no, no, no,
an unknown story awaits.
小さな勇気で　何かを変えよう
Let's change something with a little courage.
あーね
Right.
大切な話があるんだ
I have something important to tell you.
ここにない探しものがあるんだ
There's something I'm looking for that isn't here.
だから旅に出ます
So, I'm going on a journey.
そのうち帰ります
I'll be back eventually.
ちょっとだけ大人になったかもね
Maybe I've become a little bit of an adult.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
Bokura wa Minna Imi Fumei
Lyrics/Music: PinocchioP
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We're all incomprehensible.
夜が明ける
Night breaks.
朝目覚める
Wake up in the morning.
首痛めるこの身体に自分がいる
I'm in this body with a sore neck.
君と喋る
Talk to you.
飯を食べる
Eat a meal.
服を着てるそのすべてが不気味である
Wearing clothes, all of it is eerie.
なんか変だ　変だ　変だ変だ
Something's strange, strange, strange, strange.
駅の改札通り抜ける
Passing through the station ticket gate.
こんな平和　平和　平和平和
Such peace, peace, peace, peace.
当たり前で受ける
Accepted as a matter of course.
猫の名前はなんとなくタマで
The cat's name is somehow Tama.
犬の…
The dog's...
犬の名前は なんとなくポチだ
The dog's name is just Pochi for some reason.
世界は 世界は なんとなくありそうで
The world, the world, seems to exist for some reason...
存在を抱えたまま ゆるやかに溶けていくよ
...while holding onto existence, it gently dissolves.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない
No point in living, no point in trying hard. It might all be in vain.
千年後 何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
Nothing will remain in a thousand years, but I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all incomprehensible.
月が昇る 星が光る
The moon rises, the stars shine.
虫が跳ねる それを見ている
Insects jump, and I'm watching them.
いつからここにいるんだっけ
Since when have I been here?
いつまでここにいられるんだっけ
How long can I stay here?
何も何もなれないままで
Becoming nothing at all,
化け物から逃げてるだけ
just running away from monsters.
座敷牢でイメージを浮かべて
Picturing images in a prison cell,
ストップした思考は敵だらけ
my stopped thoughts are full of enemies.
太郎の名前は 今では太郎で
Taro's name is now Taro.
次郎の名前は 今では花子だ
Jiro's name is now Hanako.
時間は 時間は なんとなく通り過ぎて
Time, time, just passes by somehow.
ゴミ溜めで埋もれたまま 星空を眺めてるよ
Buried in a trash heap, I'm gazing at the starry sky.
愛する意味も 恋する意味も ないないない 嘘かもしれない
No point in loving, no point in falling in love. It might all be a lie.
1+1も よくわからんけど それでも君を守っていたい
I don't even understand 1+1, but I still want to protect you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all incomprehensible.
それでもぼくらは トンネルで息を止める
Still, we hold our breath in tunnels.
折り紙で鶴を折る
We fold cranes out of origami.
肉球を触る
We touch paw pads.
横断歩道の白い部分だけを 踏む
We step only on the white parts of the crosswalk.
それでもぼくらは 間違ったことをする
Still, we do things wrong,
正しいと思い込む
convincing ourselves they're right.
頭いいから わかっていた
I understood because I'm smart.
またわかった気になっていたんだ
I just felt like I understood again.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も
No point in living, no point in trying hard.
ないないない ないないない...
No, no, no, no, no, no...
それでもやるしかない
But still, we have to do it.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない 無駄かもしれない
No point in living, no point in trying hard. It might all be in vain.
千年後 何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
Nothing will remain in a thousand years, but I still want to laugh with you.
夢を叶えても 悟り開いても 結局は孤独かもしれない
Even if dreams come true, even if you reach enlightenment, in the end, you might be lonely.
お化けになっても 虚無に帰っても それでも君と笑っていたい
Even if I become a ghost, even if I return to nothingness, I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we're all incomprehensible.
そう ぼくらはみんな意味不明
Yes, we're all incomprehensible.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We're all incomprehensible.
だ・か・ら
Because of that.
そう簡単な祈りだった 洟から
It was such a simple prayer from the start.
だんだんと消える感嘆
Exclamations that gradually disappear.
今から どんちょうが上がるから
As the curtain rises now,
静かな会場を後にさよなら
goodbye to the quiet venue.
ロウワー
Lower
言いかけていたことが一つ 消えてまた増えて
One thing I was about to say vanishes, then another appears,
背中に後ろめたさが残る
leaving a sense of guilt behind.
したがいたい心に 根を吐き出さぬように込めて
Rooting feelings of wanting to follow into my heart so they don't leak out,
胸の中が檻のように濁る
my chest becomes murky like a cage.
受け止めたいことが 自分さえ抱えられず
I can't even handle what I want to accept,
持て余したそれを守っている
so I'm protecting it instead.
掠んだ声は空々に のどを焼いて埋め尽くす
My faint voice burns my throat in vain, filling it up.
何を言うべきかわからなくて
I don't know what I should say.
感じてたものが 遠く放たれていた
What I felt was being released far away.
同じようで違う なんだか違う
It seems the same, but it's different, somehow different.
いつまで行こうか どこまで行けるのか
How long shall we go, how far can we go?
定かじゃないなら何を想うの
If it's not certain, what are you thinking?
僕らが離れるなら 僕らが迷うなら
If we part ways, if we get lost,
その度に何回も 繋がれるように
so that we can reconnect as many times as it takes.
ここにいてくれるなら 離さずにいられたら
If you'll stay here, if I could keep hold of you,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で救われていく
we'll be saved by a sensation no one knows yet.
平穏とは消耗を以て 代わりに成す
Peace is achieved through attrition.
実際はどうも変わりはなく
In reality, nothing really changes.
享楽とは嘘で成る
Pleasure is made of lies.
綻ぶ
It unravels.
♪ ロウワー
♪ LOUWER
今は永遠にここで出ようかとお
Thinking of getting out of here for good now
通う好意に願いを
Making a wish on this mutual affection
同じように 同じように呟く
We both whisper the same thing
どこから聞こうか 何を見失うか
Where should I start listening, what will I lose sight of?
定かじゃないからここ動けない
Nothing is certain, so I can't move from here
僕らが壊れるなら
If we are to break
これ以上ないなら
If this is all there is
その度に何回も逃げ出せるように
So that we can escape time and time again
心が守れるように
So that our hearts can be protected
奪われないように
So that they won't be stolen away
互いに託してから 身体を預けてよ
Entrusting it to each other, leave your body to me
君と泣く
Cry with you
君と笑う
Laugh with you
君と怒る
Get angry with you
君と歌う
Sing with you
君と踊る
Dance with you
君と話す
Talk with you
いつまで続くだろうと
Wondering how long this will last
同じように 同じように呟く
We both whisper the same thing
今忘れないよう 刻まれた空気を
So as not to forget the atmosphere etched here
これから何度思い出すのだろう
I wonder how many times I'll recall it from now on
僕らが離れるなら
If we are to part
僕らが迷うなら
If we are to lose our way
その度に何回も繋がれるように
So that we can be connected time and time again
ここにいてくれるなら
If you'll stay here for me
離さずやれたら
If we can keep from letting go
まだ誰も知らない感覚で僕の
With a sensation that no one else knows yet
生きてる全てを確かめて正しくして
Confirm my whole life and make it right
Very expected we are
♪ UNDEAD
UNHAPPY? / BE HAPPY!
悩める人の子よ
Oh, child of man, who worries
人ならざるものも
And even those who are not human
絶えず目指せよ
Strive for it constantly
目覚めているんだし
Since you're wide awake
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
The past you turned away from, and the boring future too
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh boy
古今東西 ピースピース
From all times and places, peace peace
UNDEAD / 作詞・作曲：Ayase
UNDEAD / Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
UNHAPPY / ALUCKY
BE HAPPY / UNDEAD
ねねねねね 何だかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, hey, for some reason
戦ってるような そんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting somehow
止められない 触れたくもない
Can't be stopped, don't even want to touch
正真正銘 この自分？自分？自分？
Is this really me? Me? Me?
どうも とっくに死んでる
Hello, I've been dead for a long time
透明な亡霊と対決
Facing off against a transparent ghost
痛いけど 痛い 記憶の奥
It hurts, but it hurts deep in my memories
残念 もう居ないのに
Too bad, even though I'm gone
あれ そっちがいいアイロニー
Oh, that's a nice irony
透かされてるのは 現在の自分？
Am I the one being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label
いえす 弱コンプレックス
Yes, a minor complex
とり憑かれてるみたい
It's like I'm possessed
巻き付いたまま まだ 離れない
Wrapped around and still won't let go
在りし日の自分
Myself from days gone by
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
I'm not dead, the chain of you and you
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
Living means to keep on changing
理想に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for ideals and be satisfied
幸せになろうとしないなんて嘘だ
It's a lie that you're not trying to be happy
奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
Strange, strange fantasy
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will it be a demon or a snake next?
出会って 出会ってやっと始まる物語
A story that finally begins through meetings
さあ人か化物か 可忘球大ピースピース
Now, human or monster? Piece piece
PAST and FUTURE can't end the past
PAST and FUTURE run for the future
コココココ 何だかどうして
He-he-he-he-hey, for some reason
未来になんてなれんの
How can I become the future?
希望なんて 期待できない
Hope isn't something I can expect
ような気がして
Or so it feels
もう随分生きている
I've been living for a long time
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with deja vu and templates
素敵な出来事の気配もない
Not a sign of anything wonderful happening
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Too bad, the karma of experience gained
汚染された神話と退屈な進化
A tainted myth and boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Simply put, I want excitement
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm bored, I'm used to it
整っていくガイダンス
Orderly guidance
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
満たされていくみたい
Seems like I'm being fulfilled
擦り尽くして あれも これも どれも
Worn down, this, that, and everything
同じ味がする
All tastes the same
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
I'm not dead, the chain of you and you
いつの世も過去も 未来も今にあるんだ
All eras, past, and future exist in the now
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Faithfully fulfill the act of living
目指せハッピーエンド
Strive for a happy ending
死んじゃいない お前に言ってるんだ
I'm not dead, I'm talking to you
悪魔の踊り方
作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
Akuma no Odorikata
Lyrics & Composition: Tatsuya Kitani
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った
The devil said that emotions are useless no matter what.
何もかも捨てちまえよ
Throw everything away.
嗚呼　一杯の喜怒哀楽さえも
Ah, even a mouthful of joy, anger, grief, and pleasure.
どうしようもない事実　ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
An unavoidable fact: humans cannot escape the end.
何も抗えない欲望に従え
Submit to the desires you cannot resist.
思考を休めるな脳味噌を回せ
Don't let your thoughts rest, keep your brain spinning.
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"Nobody is looking at you anyway."
おかしくなってしまうことをどうして恥じる？
Why be ashamed of going crazy?
お前らに完璧で間違った
Because I'll teach you the perfect and
踊り方を教えてやるから
wrong way to dance.
いっせーので捨てちまえ
On the count of three, throw it away,
そんな命ならば
if that's all your life is worth.
何十何百何千何万回
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands,
学習しなさいな
tens of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ　空っぽの骸骨だろ
No matter what, you're an empty skeleton, aren't you?
わかっているのかい
Do you understand?
感情なんていつ何時でも邪魔だって悪魔は言った
The devil said that emotions are a nuisance at any time.
反論の余地などない
There is no room for argument.
嗚呼　人生に意味を与えておくれ
Ah, please give meaning to my life.
420でさえも救えない
I learned there's an end that
終焉があると知った
even 420 cannot save.
誰も疑わない神様を疑え
Doubt the god that nobody doubts.
思考を休めるな脳味噌を回せ
Don't let your thoughts rest, keep your brain spinning.
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"Nobody is looking at you anyway."
躊躇っている
Know the futility of
数秒の無益さを知れ
those few seconds of hesitation.
お前らに完璧で間違った
Because I'll teach you the perfect and
踊り方を教えてやるから
wrong way to dance.
いっせーので捨てちまえ
On the count of three, throw it away,
そんな命ならば
if that's all your life is worth.
何十何百何千何万回
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands,
学習しなさいな
tens of thousands of times.
どうしたってさ　頭ン中空っぽなことわかっていないようだな
No matter what, it seems you don't realize your head is empty.
承認欲にレイプされ
A woman raped by the desire for approval,
死んだ花をぶら下げている女
hanging dead flowers.
何かを愛することすらままならないまま
Unable to even love something,
餌を待つだけ
just waiting for bait.
踊り方を知らない
To those who don't know how to dance
芸術の価値などわからない奴らに
and don't understand the value of art...
堕落していれば何も見えないまま
While falling into corruption, you see nothing.
真善美に背いた
Because I'll teach you a way to dance
踊り方を教えてやるから
that defies truth, goodness, and beauty.
いっせーので狂っちまえ
On the count of three, go mad
惨めな姿で
in your miserable state.
何十何百何千何万
Among tens, hundreds, thousands,
何億人の中でさ
tens of thousands, hundreds of millions.
そうして埋もれていったっていいと
How can you say it's fine
どうして言えるのだろう
to be buried like that?
ねえ、世界が煩っている狂信は
Hey, the fanaticism the world is suffering from...
健常者でさえ目が眩むような
Is emitting a light that would
光を放っている
dazzle even a healthy person.
今夜、悪魔がお前らに乞うぜ
Tonight, the devil makes a plea to you.
神とやらに惑わされるなよ
Don't be deceived by this thing called god.
はーい！「悪魔の踊り方」、歌わせていただきましたー！
Hi! I just sang "Akuma no Odorikata"!
いやー、「悪魔の踊り方」ってさ、
Man, "Akuma no Odorikata"
すごいかっこいい曲じゃない？
is such a cool song, isn't it?
ああいう、かっこいい歌歌うと、
When I sing cool songs like that,
なんか、ちゃんと様になっているのかなーって、
I wonder if I'm pulling it off properly...
なんか、心細い気持ちに実はなってるんだよね。
I actually start to feel a bit insecure.
ちゃんと、かっこよく歌えてたかな？僕。
Did I manage to sing it coolly?
はい！ということでね、なんかもー、
Alright! And so, everything up to this point
ここまで、もうあっという間だったよね。
has gone by in a flash, hasn't it?
もうこんな時間経ってるんだーっていう感じでございますが、
It feels like "wow, has it been this long already?" but...
なんとですね！ここから告知タイムとさせていただきたいと思いまーす！
Guess what! From here, I'd like to move on to the announcement segment!
はい、ということで、
Alright, so...
まずはみんなに見ていただきたいCMがございます！
first, there's a CM I'd like everyone to see!
やばい、みんな心して！
It's incredible, everyone get ready!
どうぞ！
Here it is!
檜山修之が
Hiyama Nobuyuki
ここからは檜山修之が猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2026のグッズをご紹介するぞ！
From here on, Hiyama Nobuyuki will introduce the Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration 2026 goods!
まずはこれだ！はっぴ〜おかゆはっぴ！
First up is this! The Happy Okayu Happi!
神岡ちろる先生の描き下ろしイラストが描かれた法被がグッズになったぞ。
A happi featuring a new illustration by Kamioka Chirol-sensei is now available.
きょとん顔のおかゆんがとてもキュート！
Okayun's blank expression is so cute!
イベントやライブに着ていけば、一目で「おにぎりゃー」アピールできるスーパーハッピーなグッズだ！
Wear it to events or lives and you'll immediately show your "Onigiri-ya" pride! It's a super happy item!
お出かけに連れてって！アクリルスタンド！
Take it with you on outings! The Acrylic Stand!
アクスタはもう家に飾るだけの時代じゃない！
Acrylic stands aren't just for decorating your home anymore!
日々のお出かけを彩る、推し活マストアイテム。
A must-have fan item to color your daily outings.
ポーチに入れて外に持ち運んで、おかゆんに世界をたくさん見せてあげてくれよな！
Put it in your pouch, take it outside, and show Okayun much more of the world!
ごくごく！BIGたんぶら〜
Gulp gulp! The BIG Tumbler~
甘城なつき先生描き下ろしのミニキャラが描かれた大容量のタンブラー。
A large-capacity tumbler featuring mini-characters newly drawn by Amashiro Natsuki-sensei.
持ち手やストローもついているので、外出時はもちろん、勉強中や仕事中、様々なシチュエーションで大活躍間違いなし！
With a handle and straw, it's perfect for outings, studying, working—useful in all sorts of situations!
おかゆんの配信を見るときにも使ってくれ！
Be sure to use it while watching Okayun's streams too!
おでかけおにぎり型ショルダーポーチ！
The Outing Onigiri-shaped Shoulder Pouch!
アクスタやホロライブフレンズ with uなど、ちょっとした小物が入る優れたショルダーポーチだぜ。
An excellent shoulder pouch that can hold small items like acrylic stands or Hololive Friends with u.
透明素材なので日々のおしかつに使える一品となっているぞ！
Made of transparent material, it's a perfect item for your daily fan activities!
そして…フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And... here is the full set purchase bonus!
なんとフルセットを購入した全員に、猫又おかゆ直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてくる！
Incredibly, everyone who purchases the full set will receive a postcard with Nekomata Okayu's handwritten signature and a duplicated message!
おにぎりゃーのみんな、絶対ゲットしてくれよな！
All you Onigiri-ya out there, make sure you get one!
やばーい！
That was amazing!
ということで、あの、檜山修之さんに生誕グッズのCMを撮っていただきました！やばい！
So, um, Hiyama Nobuyuki-san actually recorded the CM for my birthday goods! Incredible!
檜山修之さんというね、あの、レジェンドの声優さんがいらっしゃいまして...
There's this legendary voice actor named Hiyama Nobuyuki-san...
猫又おかゆ、ホロライブデビュー時から、世界で一番大好きな声優さんとなっております。
and ever since my Hololive debut, he's been my favorite voice actor in the whole world.
あの、この場をお借りして、あの、檜山修之さん本当にありがとうございました。
Um, I'd like to take this opportunity to say: Hiyama Nobuyuki-san, thank you so much.
ちょ、興奮冷めやらぬなんですが...
Wait, I'm still so excited, but...
CMにあった通り、猫又おかゆ生誕グッズ2026を発売させていただきますので、皆さん是非ご予約お待ちしてます！
as shown in the CM, the Nekomata Okayu Birthday Goods 2026 are going on sale, so I'll be waiting for your pre-orders!
そして、告知は1つだけじゃないんですね！
And that's not the only announcement!
続きましてはこちら、ドドン！
Moving on, here's the next one—ta-da!
いよいよお待ちかね！来月3月26日木曜日に「おかゆにゅ〜む！R」...
Finally, the moment you've been waiting for! On Thursday, March 26th, next month, "Okayu-nyu-mu! R"...
ん？
Huh?
R！
R!
んー、おかゆにゅ〜む！Rがリリース！
Mmm, Okayu-nyu-mu! R is being released!
青森を舞台に、君と2人で商品開発という名の恋人旅行がスタート！
Set in Aomori, a lover's trip for the two of us begins under the guise of product development!
笑いあり、デートあり、夜警権？もあり...
There's laughter, dates, and even... night watch duty rights?
の、盛りだくさんな作品となっております。自分でさ、夜警権ありって何言ってんだって思っちゃったね、うん。
It's a work packed with content. I thought to myself, "What am I even saying with 'night watch duty rights'?"
自分で言ったくせにね。僕が夜警権ありたいって言ったくせにね。
Even though I'm the one who said it. Even though I said I wanted night watch duty rights.
そして、夜警権あるのにCERO審査大丈夫なの？というお声、度々いただいておりますが...
And I often get comments like, "Is the CERO rating okay even with night watch duty rights?"
なんと、心配していたCERO審査も無事Cで決まりました！
Well, the CERO rating we were worried about has been safely decided as C!
ふー、良かった良かった。んー。
Phew, what a relief. Mmm.
皆体験版も、もう既に遊んでくれたかな？
I wonder if everyone has already played the trial version?
あのドキドキの続きは、是非君の目で確かめてほしいな。
I want you to see the continuation of that excitement with your own eyes.
まだまだたくさんの未公開情報もあるとのことなので、おかゆにゅ〜む！Rから目が離せないよ！
There's still a lot of unreleased information, so keep your eyes on "Okayu-nyu-mu! R"!
是非お楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
そしてこちら、最後の告知となります。
And this will be the final announcement.
毎年発表させていただいているんですが、今日もライブの最後に新曲を発表させていただきます！
As I do every year, I'm going to announce a new song at the end of today's live!
はあ、やっと言えた。
Phew, I finally said it.
今回はですね、てにをはさんに作詞作曲をしていただきました。ありがとうございます、てにをはさん。
This time, Teniwoha-san wrote the lyrics and composed the music. Thank you, Teniwoha-san.
でわでわ、あの、色々言いたいこととかもあるんですが...
Well then, um, there are many things I want to say, but...
まずは、君の目でしっかり聴いていただければな、
First, I'd like you to listen carefully with your own eyes,
見ていただければなと思っております。
and see for yourself.
でわでわ、
Well then,
聴いてください。
Please listen.
「ノンデリシャス」
“Non-Delicious”
ノンデリシャス 作詞・作曲・編曲：てにをは
Non-Delicious / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Teniwoha
今日もカムカム 1, 2, 3
Today as well, chew chew 1, 2, 3
舌も踊るよ 1, 2, 3
Even the tongue dances 1, 2, 3
トラウマをじっくり煮込んだボルシチどうぞ
Here's a borscht with trauma slowly simmered
君の心臓はハガタだらけさ
Your heart is full of bite marks
苦肉のステーキとセルフィッシュなチップス
A steak of desperation and selfish chips
マンネリを刻んだサラダ
A salad with chopped-up ruts
こんなにも美味しい食卓 邪魔しないで
Don't disturb such a delicious table
お口を開けて はい あーん
Open your mouth and say "Ahhh"
ウェイター ウェイター お皿を下げないで
Waiter, waiter, don't take the plate away
これがボクの "おいしいモノ" なんだから
Because this is my "delicious thing"
ハングリー ハングリー グラトニー 新しいメニュー
Hungry, hungry, gluttony, a new menu
みんなクワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone, quiet, quiet, what you've been waiting for
デ・デ・デ・リシャス デリ・デリシャス
De-de-de-licious, deli-delicious
ノン・デ・デ・デ・リシャス デリ・デリシャス
Non-de-de-de-licious, deli-delicious
そんなテリブル・テーブル蹴飛ばして
Kick away that terrible table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないで
Don't gobble every day, every night
ノンデリシャス なんべんだっておかわり
Non-delicious, seconds no matter how many times
お皿積み上げ 3, 4, 5
Stacking plates 3, 4, 5
バベルみたいに 3, 4, 5
Like Babel 3, 4, 5
喉の奥につっかえて窒息しかけても
Even if it gets stuck in the back of your throat...
大人は飲み込むらしい すごいね
Adults apparently swallow it down, impressive
見栄っ張りのソテー 義理人情サンドイッチ
Show-off saute, duty and sentiment sandwich
情熱の冷めたスープ
Passion-less cooled soup
そんなもの頼んでいないから
I didn't order such a thing
ボクはボクで好きなものだけ食べるだけ
I'll just eat what I like on my own
ウェイター ウェイター 際限なく持ってきて
Waiter, waiter, bring it without limits
これがボクの "おいしい日々" なんだから
Because these are my "delicious days"
イロハロン モロモロ 飲み込んだ後で
After swallowing various basics
挑めダイエット
Challenge a diet
一心不乱に噛む カム 不条理を噛む
Chew single-mindedly, chew, chew on absurdity
のらりくらり 幸せそうな顔して
Elusively, making a happy face
噛む 噛む あくまで噛む
Chew, chew, chew to the bitter end
みんなクワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone, quiet, quiet, what you've been waiting for
デ・デ・デ・リシャス デリ・デリシャス
De-de-de-licious, deli-delicious
ノン・デ・デ・デ・リシャス デリ・デリシャス
Non-de-de-de-licious, deli-delicious
そんなテリブル・テーブル蹴飛ばして
Kick away that terrible table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないで
Don't gobble every day, every night
ノンデリシャス でもなんべんだっておかわりしよう
Non-delicious, but let's have seconds no matter how many times
はあ...
Sigh...
ノンデリシャス
Non-Delicious
猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026 WeirdCookies
Nekomata Okayu Birthday Festival 2026 WeirdCookies
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
オムカ
Omuka
〈グッズ映像制作〉 白水
Shiromizu
〈VJ映像制作〉 Syano.S -しゃもじ- / Polna / 根本 欄 / オムカ / Lye / hotori
Syano.S, Polna, Ran Nemoto, Omuka, Lye, hotori
〈歌詞テロップ映像制作〉 金借りカレー
Kanekari Curry
〈サムネイルイラスト制作〉 せとかね
Setokane
〈ステージロゴ制作〉 コマチャン！
Komachan!
〈制作〉 COVER Corp. STUDIO
COVER Corp. STUDIO
おにぎりゃー！！
Onigirya!!
今日は お祝いしてくれて 本当にありがとう><///
Thank you so much for celebrating today with me! ><///
毎日ハッピーなのも 君のおかげ♡
Being happy every day is all thanks to you. ♡
ずっと一緒にいたいね。♡♡
I want to be together with you forever. ♡♡
ちょっとでも君の笑顔の きっかけになれますように...
I hope I can be a reason for your smile, even just a little...
猫又おかゆ 2026.02.22
Nekomata Okayu - Feb 22, 2026